# **Alex Clark**



Email: aclark@aclark.net | Website: http://aclark.net

## **About**

Alex Clark is a **Python Web Developer** from Baltimore, Maryland, USA living in Bethesda, Maryland. He has a **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** from Loyola University in Maryland and has worked as a **Network Engineer**, **Software Engineer**, **Systems Administrator** and **Technical Team Leader** since May, 1998. He is also the **President of DC Python**, a non-profit organization he co-founded to promote and support the use of Python software in DC.

# **Profiles**

# GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter

## **Skills**

Web Development	Python	Systems	Networking
• HTML	• Django	Apple macOS Unix	• TCP/IP
• CSS	Pyramid	Ubuntu Linux	• CIFS
JavaScript	• Plone	CentOS Linux	• NFS
	• Zope	Microsoft Windows	• DNS

# **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

**Loyola University Maryland** 

January, 1999

http://www.loyola.edu/academics/computer-science

# **Work Experience**

## **ACLARK.NET, LLC**

## Partner & Python Web Developer

2004 — Present

http://aclark.net

- Develop and deploy, support and maintain Python web applications with Django, Plone, Pyramid & Zope and related technologies e.g. HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- Serve government, non-profit and private sector clients e.g. NASA, National Geographic Society and Socialcode (a Washington Post company.)
- Develop and maintain complex IT infrastructure with Amazon Web Services (AWS), CloudFlare, Rackspace Cloud, etc.
- Provide production operations support.
- Write articles on technical subjects, publish to professional blog: http://blog.aclark.net.

# Neurophysiology Imaging Facility (NIF) $\rightarrow$ Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) $\rightarrow$ National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) $\rightarrow$ National Institutes of Health (NIH)

#### **Systems Administrator**

March, 2013 — Present

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Evaluate and recommend hardware and software for purchase by NIF.
- Install, configure and maintain hardware and software.
- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software problems.
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and backups.
- Manage network and system security.
- Analyze network performance and access to public resources.
- Provide desktop support to NIF staff, resolve productivity issues.
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues.

# Scientific and Statistical Computing Core (SSCC) $\rightarrow$ Division of Intramural Research Programs (DIRP) $\rightarrow$ National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) $\rightarrow$ National Institutes of Health (NIH)

May, 2002 — October, 2005

#### **Systems Administrator**

http://www.nimh.nih.gov/labs-at-nimh/research-areas/research-support-services

- Research and recommend hardware for purchase.
- Install, configure and maintain server and desktop hardware.

- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware problems.
- Install, configure and maintain operating systems, web server, content management system, FTP server, directory services, file sharing services, revision control system, and tape backups.
- Manage network and system security.
- Analyze network performance and access to public resources.
- Provide desktop support to SSCC members, resolved productivity issues.
- Provide liaison to NIH CIT on infrastructure and security related issues.
- Manage content management system, provide instruction to SSCC members on how to add and edit content.
- Design and implement new site technology.
- Respond to and resolve web site issues for the SSCC and AFNI community.

## Genuity

#### **Network Engineer**

October, 1998 — November, 2001

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBN\_Technologies

- Developed Perl and Expect software to support remote configuration of over 2,000 Cisco 2511 Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers, and Cisco Catalyst 1900/2820 Ethernet Switches.
- Developed Perl CGI software to support remote configuration of access servers with over 4 ingress T1 data lines via SNMP e.g. Cisco 5400, Lucent APX 8000, Nortel CVX 1800.
- Configured over 2,000 Cisco Access Servers, Equinox Terminal Servers and Cisco Catalyst Ethernet Switches.
- Installed and configured Debian Linux, Redhat Linux, Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Configured Linux kernel to support myriad network interface cards.
- Researched and resolved complex network connectivity issues.
- Verified successful negotiation of TCP, PPP and L2TP protocols through dial-up connections between client programs and remote access servers.
- Performed maintenance on AOLnet and BBN Dialinx dial-up networks.
- Provided production operations support.

## **Charm Net**

#### **Systems Administrator**

January, 1998 — August, 1998

http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20070125005632/en/DataPoint-Acquires-Award-Winning-Charm-Net

- Managed 4 BSDI Unix servers for over 2,000 users.
- Installed and configured DNS, NFS, Sendmail, Apache, INND and Dump/Restore.
- Installed and configured hardware and software for streaming FM radio to the internet.
- Installed and configured BSDI Unix servers and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

## **Loyola University Maryland**

#### **Help Desk Consultant & Student Technician**

August, 1996 — November, 1997

http://www.loyola.edu/department/technology-services

- Provided telephone and in-person technical support to students, faculty, and administrators.
- Performed installation, maintenance, and trouble-shooting of hardware and software in labs, offices, and dormitories.
- Installed and configured Sun Microsystems Solaris Unix, Slackware Linux, Redhat Linux and Microsoft Windows workstations and servers.
- Provided production operations support.

## **Volunteer Work**

## **Pillow**

#### Fork Author & Project Leader

July, 2010 — Present

http://python-pillow.org

- Forked popular Python Imaging Library (PIL) software to create frequently-updated and well-maintained version.
- Foster growth of core development team from single member to five members over five years.
- Write and submit grant proposal to fund Python 3 compatible version of Pillow; sent to Python Software Foundation February 28, 2013; passed unanimously on March 4, 2013.
- Implement and manage quarterly release schedule.
- Continuously oversee development to ensure best possible quality of releases.

# Parkwood Residents Association (PRA)

#### **Webmaster & Executive Committee Member**

2014 — Present

http://parkwoodresidents.org

- Maintain website for PRA to serve residents of Parkwood community in Bethesda, MD.
- Attend committee and resident meetings to participate in discussions about community issues.
- Vote in quorum to affect decisions related to PRA actions.

# **DC Python**

#### Co-Founder & President

2008 — Present

http://dcpython.org

- Co-founded 501(c)(3) non-profit organization to promote & support Python software in DC.
- Envisioned, co-organized and co-hosted Plone Conference 2008 in DC; largest yearly gathering of Plone CMS developers; first east coast USA location since inaugural event in 2003.

## **Awards**

# **Startup Row Winner PyCon 2012**

## **PythonPackages**

March, 2012

http://pythonpackages.com

"PythonPackages began in October 2011 as a fun way to provide useful information to the Python community. Since then hundreds of folks have visited the site to feature their favorite Python packages, for a total of over 10K packages featured. New features have come regularly, and some new features are waiting in the wings, about to be launched."

## **Publications**

## Plone 3.3 Site Administration

#### **PACKT Publishing Limited**

July, 2010

https://www.packtpub.com/web-development/plone-33-site-administration

"Manage your site like a Plone professional."